lorainccc.edu 2018-10-04

# Web Site Privacy Policy - Policies and Academic Standards

Information and services offered on lorainccc.edu are provided by Lorain County Community College, Elyria, Ohio. The purpose of the site is to provide public information about the college, and to offer online services to students, college faculty and staff. Online services include, but are not limited to college admission, class registration, tuition payment, financial aid and class schedules. Lorain County Community College recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy rights of our users. Any information shared between users and Lorain County Community College is securely managed and safeguarded in accordance with all applicable laws and the policies and guidelines set forth below.

**Changes to privacy policy  
**Lorain County Community College may need to change our privacy statement because of changes in the law, in technology, in Lorain County Community College’s business, or in our attempts to serve your needs better. We will use every effort to communicate in a timely manner any changes to our privacy statement in the manner described in the Lorain County Community College Site Terms and Conditions.

**What information does Lorain County Community College gather?  
**Online services that are accessible through lorainccc.edu provide password-protected access to individuals’ personal records including, but not limited to, personal contact information, class records information and tuition-payment history. This information is accessible only by the individual and approved college administrative staff.

**How the information is used  
**Information captured in lorainccc.edu and enables users to access their personal records and utilize online services offered by Lorain County Community College.

**Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act  
**The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) of 1974, as amended, provides students access to information about themselves, permits students to challenge such information about themselves, and limits the release of such information about students without the student’s explicit written consent.

LCCC is committed to this Act in its entirety. [Procedural guidelines are available by clicking here](https://www.lorainccc.edu/policies/campus-policies/family-educational-rights-and-privacy-act/ "FERPA"), in appropriate College publications, and copies of procedures may be obtained from the Records Office.

**Access to student records  
**A student’s record, with certain exceptions including directory information (see below), will not be released without prior written consent of the student. A student has the right to review and question the content of her/his educational record within a reasonable time (45 days) after making a written request for such a review. If there are any questions as to the accuracy or appropriateness of the record that cannot be resolved informally, an opportunity for a hearing on the matter will be provided.

**Disclosure of education records  
**LCCC will disclose information from a student’s educational records only with the written consent of the student, except:

  * To school officials who have a legitimate educational interest in the records
  * To certain officials of the U.S. Department of Education, the comptroller general, and state and local educational authorities, in connection with certain state or federally supported education programs
  * In connection with a student’s request for or receipt of financial aid, as necessary to determine the eligibility, amount or conditions of the financial aid, or to enforce the terms and conditions of the aid
  * If required by a state law requiring disclosure that was adopted before November 19, 1974
  * To organizations conducting certain studies for or on behalf of the College
  * To accrediting organizations to carry out their functions
  * To comply with a judicial order or a lawfully issued subpoena
  * To appropriate parties in a health or safety emergency

**Directory information  
**LCCC designates certain personally identifiable information that is contained within the student’s education record as “directory information” so that the College may, at its discretion, disclose this information without a student’s prior written consent. This information is student name, home address and telephone number, e-mail address, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized activities, current enrollment status (including dates of attendance, full or part time, withdrawal status). A student may restrict the publication and release of this directory information by filing a written request with the Records Office.

In addition, the following information is always considered releasable: previous dates of attendance, degrees and awards received (to include honors), previous educational agencies or institutions attended. The complete policy regarding the collection, retention and dissemination of information about a student is available in the Records Office.

**Cookies  
**Our website may places “cookies” on your computer, unless your browser is set to reject cookies. The cookies enable our website to recognize you when you return to the website at a later date or time and enables us to personalize the website with preferences or information you have provided during prior sessions.

**Links to other websites  
**Our website may contain links to other public or private entities’ websites, whose privacy practices we do not control.

**Choice to provide information  
**There is no requirement for you to provide any information at our website. However, the online services will not be available to you without proper login. Failure of your browser to provide nonessential technical information will not prevent your use of our website, but may prevent you from accessing online services.

**Visitor comments or review  
**If you have questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this website or if you choose to review or correct any information, please contact us at [webmaster@lorainccc.edu](mailto:webmaster@lorainccc.edu), or call (800) 366-5222.
